<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Simulation on LeaRning Stats</title>
    <link>/tags/simulation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Simulation on LeaRning Stats</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/simulation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>On power and effect size</title>
      <link>/2018/11/09/on-power-and-effect-size/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/11/09/on-power-and-effect-size/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I have seen a lot of tweets on my feed about power and effect size. I wanted to think about those things carefully, so I did some reading and am writing down some thoughts. An interesting paper that I read on this is here The takeaway is that studies that are underpowered, yet still obtain statistically significant results, will tend to overestimate the effect size.
 Simulations Let’s imagine that we are doing a hypothesis test of \(\mu = 0\) versus \(\mu \not = 0\), and our underlying population is normal with mean 1 and standard deviation 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Copula Sampling</title>
      <link>/2018/11/01/copula-sampling/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/11/01/copula-sampling/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I was reading about different ways to sample from distributions, and one that caught my eye was based on copulas. There is an answer here, but there seemed to be enough details left to the reader that I wanted to just do it.
One variable example To start, let’s remind ourselves about the “universality of the uniform” for one-dimensional data. If \(X\) is a (continuous) random variable with distribution function \(F\), then \(F(X)\) is uniform(0, 1).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prediction Bands</title>
      <link>/2018/04/07/prediction-bands/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/04/07/prediction-bands/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In this post, we study a seemingly easy question; what is a 95% prediction interval in simple linear regression? We assume that our data comes from \[ y_i = 1 + 2x_i + \epsilon_i \] where \(\epsilon_i\) are iid normal with mean 0 and standard deviation 3.
 R Code for Prediction We can build a linear model and prediction intervals using the following R code:
set.seed(4172018) x &amp;lt;- runif(30, 0, 10) y &amp;lt;- 1 + 2 * x + rnorm(30, 0, 3) mod &amp;lt;- lm(y~x) predict(mod, newdata = data.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>